GIRL: So even if Columbus got lost and
wasn't the first to discover America,
he's still my hero.
He was really brave to sail such a
tiny ship over a really big ocean,
and because of him, we get Columbus Day
off of school.
Thank you, Heather.
Ronnie, tell us about your hero.
What's he writing?
Hachiko was my grandfather
Wilson's dog.
(STUDENTS LAUGHING)
Everyone called Hachi
a mystery dog
because they never really knew where
he came from.
(BELL RINGING)
RONNIE: Maybe Hachi
escaped from a dog pound.
Or maybe he jumped out
of somebody's car
from someplace far away like
Florida or New Jersey.
(BELL RINGING)
But no matter how,
Hachi was lost.
(CHANTING)
(HACHI WHIMPERING)
(TROLLEY RATTLING)
(MEN CHATTERING)
Hey, it's a little puppy.
(MAN CHATTERING ON PA)
RONNIE: But no matter
how It happened,
a long time ago, in the town
my grandfather lived in,
Hachi appeared
at the train station,
and that's where
their story began.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(HACHI WHIMPERING)
PARKER: No, it was great.
I loved the musicians.
No, no, no,
I'll walk. I'll walk.
Yeah, I love you, too. Bye.
Hey, buddy. Are you lost?
Come here.
You lost here, bud?
Someone must be
looking for you.
Little guy was
wandering around.
CARL: Really? Out
on the platform?
On the platform, yeah.
Well, good for you
for finding him.
Yeah.
Well, I'll tell you what.
This little crate was
out there. It was broken.
I don't know
what's going on, but...
Oh.
Anyhow, someone's gonna be here for him.
Yeah.
So if you'll just hold him here.
You just hold him
till they come.
No, I can't do that.
I can't do that,
Professor.
Well, he was out... No one's gonna leave this dog.
There's...
No, I know that.
I know no one's gonna leave it.
They'll be back for it.
So you take him with you,
and when anyone shows up,
I'll tell them that you have him.
Someone's gonna be here.
They're gonna come for him.
No, you don't understand.
Really, just, just...
I'm gonna have to put this in here for like the
whole night if nobody comes.
If they're not here, I'll lock him in here and
he'll be safe for the night,
but all I can do is take him to the
pound in the morning.
(SIGHING)
Good thing it's Friday,
you know?
We'll find out where you're headed.
Until then, you can stay with me
in a nice warm house.
How's that? Yeah?
All right.
Here you go.
Sit right here. Sit right there.
Okay, yeah. Here you go.
Okay. Stay, stay.
Chew on those. It's okay.
Stay.
(HACHI YELPING)
(SHUSHING)
Hello, handsome.
Hi.
Hi. How'd it go?
It was great.
Good. You miss me?
Not a bit. You?
No. Didn't think
about you once.
I have a little surprise.
Yeah, well, I have a little
surprise for you, too.
Come on. We have
some catching up to do.
Yeah.
Catching up.
Okay, we'll catch up.
(ORGAN SOUNDING)
Did you hear something?
PARKER:
That was a branch
against the window.
PARKER: I ran into this interesting
situation at the station tonight.
(YELPING)
CATE:
Why don't you tell me about it in the morning?
How does that sound?
PARKER: What
am I gonna do?
(HACHI SNIFFING)
(SCREAMING)
Okay, okay.
Okay, it's all right.
Parker!
We had an agreement.
I know, I know.
Or did you forget?
No, I didn't forget.
No, it was... He was at the train station.
I mean, just kind of lost.
Carl was gonna send him to the pound
tomorrow and I thought...
You just thought you'd bring him home
and talk me into keeping him, right?
No, no, I don't want
to keep him. I don't.
Tomorrow morning
I'm getting up,
and I'll find out exactly
where he belongs, okay?
I promise you,
I will do that.
All right.
This was Luke's stuff.
Okay, okay.
Okay, here you go.
In there.
There you go.
Now look. Lots of good stuff here.
That's warm.
You got that.
It's pretty cold.
You like this? Yeah?
This was Luke's favorite.
Okay. Okay,
here's your water.
Some story you could tell, huh?
Couldn't you? Yeah.
Okay, buddy.
That's better.
Good night, buddy.
(DOOR CLOSES)
CATE: You know, you're the one who
should be in the doghouse.
PARKER: I promise
I won't bite your toe.
(WHIMPERING)
Puppy! Puppy!
CATE: Hey, puppy!
Puppy! Puppy, come on!
That's good.
(EXCLAIMING)
Good puppy.
Dad, I love him.
Does he have a name yet?
Yes, he does.
"Temporary Guest. "
(PLAYING PIANO)
You have to keep him.
Dad, the house feels so empty since
Luke's been gone.
Ask your mother.
Mom?
CATE: Yeah?
Could you come here, please?
Look, he even
likes your music.
Really!
I can't believe it!
This is a wonder dog!
I absolutely have
to keep this dog.
No more dogs.
Don't encourage him.
I won't.
You're so mean.
Dad, he's gonna
jump out of that. Here.
Oh, yeah,
that's great.
Try this.
I love it.
Does he fit?
I think so.
You in there, bud? Yeah!
No, that's good.
I like it. Great.
So, you saw
Michael last night?
Yeah.
We drove over to the look-out,
watched the comets.
It was beautiful.
Very romantic.
It was.
WOMAN: Definitely
happened more often...
Whoa!
Are you the...
Can I help you, pal?
Yeah, yeah. I just found this little guy
at the station last night.
Can you board him
until we find his owner?
Board him? No,
we can't board him.
This isn't a boarding service.
It's a pound, pal.
Look, I just found him.
What am I gonna do with him?
Let's see.
Yeah.
He's cute. That'll help with adoption,
but we give them two weeks.
(DOGS WHIMPERING)
Come on.
Two weeks?
Yeah. We're packed.
Excuse me.
MARY ANNE: I'll call you next week then.
All right. Bye-bye.
Morning, Mary Anne.
How you doing, Parker?
I'm doing great. I was wondering if
I could ask you for a favor.
Sure, anything.
(SIGHING)
(EXCLAIMING)
Look at this!
Hey, little one!
Hello. Hello!
Oh, he's gorgeous!
Where'd you come from?
He was wandering around the station
last night.
Hi, sweetheart.
I don't know,
it's very strange.
Really?
He's adorable.
I just want to put
that up. Yeah?
Okay, fine, fine.
Window?
Hello. Yeah, right over there.
Any one of those.
Parker, this dog
is just fabulous.
PARKER: You wouldn't be
interested, would you?
What, the puppy?
A fine young
puppy like that.
What do you think, Antonia?
New roommate?
(HACHI YELPING)
Oh! No! Antonia!
Yeah, yeah.
(MUMBLING)
Morning, Mr. Professor.
Jasjeet.
One sugar, two cream, coming up.
Hey, what have you got there?
I got a new friend here.
You want a dog?
I prefer cash.
He'd be a great guard dog
for you, wouldn't he?
Guard dog to guard the hot dogs?
I don't think so.
(LAUGHING)
I don't think so, either.
Seriously, man,
why you want a dog?
Every day you have to walk him,
feed him, clean him, pick up the poop.
How many of these
can I have for him?
On the house.
Too much trouble.
Yeah, you're right.
Thank you, Jas.
My pleasure.
Hey, any news?
No. Nobody came,
nobody showed up, nobody called.
Nobody?
Strange. Really strange.
Can you hold him
a second?
Yeah.
You're cute.
I made up some flyers.
Would you put that up for me?
Come on.
(SIGHING)
All right, I'll put them up for you.
What a sweetheart you are.
I know, I know, I know.
Come on.
He really likes
being in the bag.
Thanks.
Professor,
no dogs on the train.
No dogs on the train.
Thank you.
(BARKING)
(PARKER SHUSHING)
(HACHI WHINING)
(HACHI BARKING)
(MIMICKING BARKING)
(MAN PLAYING PIANO)
Okay, hold on a second.
Let me try something.
We skip the repeat
of the first section
and go directly
to the lyrical section.
Okay.
Let's try that.
But just it means you've
got to build up quicker.
You don't have to...
And when we get
to the lyrical section,
just big breaths,
big breaths.
(MAN PLAYING PIANO)
PARKER:
Don't forget to breathe.
Hello.
That's great.
You don't want a puppy,
do you? You want a puppy?
(LAUGHING)
PARKER: This was
the only thing left on the crate.
Mmm. "Yamanashi. "
That's all I can read.
What's that?
It's a part
of central Japan.
No ordinary dog, Parker.
PARKER: No.
It's an Akita, or Akita,
as you'd say.
It's a very special breed.
Yeah?
PARKER: What is that?
Hachi.
What?
It's Japanese for "Eight. "
Number of good fortune.
Oh. Good fortune.
Very nice.
Hachi. Hachi.
That's a good name.
I like that.
He might have been born eighth
in the litter.
Spiritual significance
in number eight
reaches up to heaven,
comes down to Earth.
Hmm.
So what do you think?
Do you want him?
Me?
(LAUGHING) No, I think
he's made his choice.
Meaning what?
Well, meaning he's your problem,
not mine, brother.
You're not a problem,
are you?
Well...
Whether you found him
or he found you, who's to say?
It's meant to be.
He was also saying that the shoguns
bred these Akitas for combat and hunting.
So I guess in a way,
they're kind of dog royalty.
Did Ken give you any ideas where you could
find this royal dog a home?
I put up 10 flyers already.
You know, someone's
going to claim Hachi.
CATE: Who's Hachi?
This...
It's what was on his collar.
That's the symbol.
You named him?
No, I didn't...
Parker, you want
to keep him.
No, I do not.
You do. You do.
I don't want
to keep him.
Admit it. Admit it. You do.
You want to keep him.
I wasn't even thinking about it.
(CRASHING)
Yes.
Hachi?
(SIGHING)
Where'd you go?
(GASPING)
Oh, no!
Parker, that's months
of hard work!
PARKER: Cate,
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
CATE: I want him
to stay out there all night, Parker.
Yes, yes. He's not coming back in.
Do you hear me?
I hear you.
End of discussion.
I hear you. I heard you before,
I hear you right now.
(WIND HOWLING)
CATE:
Four months of work.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Hachi.
Come on, buddy.
Come on, here.
Yeah.
Yeah, you're
coming inside.
Let's go.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
PARKER: Okay.
See if I can
find you here.
Yeah, there you are.
Your bloodline goes back
at least 4, 000 years, maybe much more.
Yeah. What else
we got here?
Yeah.
You like that?
It says the
first partnership
between man and animals
was with you.
Did you know about that?
Did you know that already?
You did, didn't you? Yeah, think you did.
Shut this down.
Let's see if we can
settle you down now.
Hey, this looks
pretty good, huh?
All right, stay there.
Stay there now. Okay?
All right, stay.
(WHIMPERING)
(SHUSHING)
(BARKING)
(WHISPERING)
Stay. Stay there.
COMMENTATOR OV TV:
At some point he establishes inside
so that the Braves hitters...
Okay.
... don't lean out there
and start shooting the ball
into right field, which is what they
did in Game 2.
I'll just stay
for a little bit.
Two and one for him.
(PEOPLE CHEERING ON TV)
Runner at second, two out.
It stays fair, Lopez,
very good play to end the inning.
(PEOPLE CHEERING ON TV)
(SIGHING)
(SWITCHES TV OFF)
(HACHI YELPING)
Excuse me.
Don't...
I was just coming up.
Yeah. Yeah, sure.
(CLEARING THROAT)
(SIGHING)
Just one night. One night only, okay?
Be a good boy.
Stay there.
All right, you'll be fine.
I can't believe it.
He loves the Yankees.
No, really? Really?
He does.
Oh, this is gonna be fun.
All right, Hachi,
this is what we're gonna do.
This is a ball.
Ball, throw.
You go get it,
you bring it back, okay?
(BALL SQUEAKING)
Okay? You ready?
Go get it.
No, no, no, the ball.
Hach. Hachi. Hachi,
Hachi, Hachi. Hey, Hachi.
Hachi.
Now I'll throw it,
you bring it back, okay?
Here we go.
Go get it.
Hachi. No, no, no.
Get the ball.
Hachi, come here.
Hachi, come on.
Go get it. Come here,
come here, come here.
Hachi, Hachi.
See the ball? See the ball?
Come here.
Hachi. Hachi,
come here.
Come here. You can do this,
I know you can.
I just think you're being
a little tough about it.
The clog's in a fix and Dad's just trying
to do the right thing.
PARKER: Okay. Okay.
Mom.
PARKER: Hachi,
Hachi. The ball. Ball, ball, ball.
Get the ball.
Come on now.
He's lost it.
(PHONE RINGING)
PARKER:
Hachi. Hey, hey.
CATE: Hello?
The puppy flyers, yes.
Are you the clog's owner?
No, no one's
come forward yet.
We just want to make sure
the dog has a good home.
Could I get your number?
I'm sure my husband would want to call you.
Hold on a second,
I need to find a pen. Hold on, okay?
PARKER: Hachi, Hachi,
Hachi. Come here.
Hachi. Good.
Hachi.
(PARKER GROWLING)
ANDY: Hi, Hachi. Hachi.
Hey, Dad,
let me get a picture.
Hello?
PARKER: Hey, boy.
The clog's already
been taken.
Yes. I'm really sorry.
(LAUGHING)
Hachi.
Whoa! No, no, no!
Hach. Hach. Hach, Hach.
(LAUGHING)
Okay, come on. Come on, take it in.
Take it in.
PARKER: No, you can't go. Can't go.
I gotta go to work.
See you back
here tonight. Bye.
(WHIMPERING)
Good morning, Mr. Professor.
Good morning.
You're a little late today.
Already waiting.
Thank you.
One sugar, two cream.
MAN ON PA:
Last call for the 8: 32
express to Providence.
The final boarding call
for the 8: 32 express to Providence.
Excuse me, excuse me.
Hachi!
What are you doing here?
What are you doing?
You gotta go
home, okay? Go.
No, go home.
Go home, go on.
I gotta get
on the train. Go, go.
Okay, come on. Gotta go home.
Come on.
Professor, you
want me to hold it?
Yeah, could you?
CARL: Thirty seconds.
Thanks.
Go home, go home.
Okay, go. Go on, go home.
Hey, Chuck, we're holding it up
for a moment, all right?
Go home. Go home!
Go, go, go!
Go on home. Come on, Hachi,
go on home.
Go home, go on.
CARL: He's really got him
trained, doesn't he?
Good boy!
CARL: Professor?
Okay. Thanks, Carl.
You sure?
Yeah, yeah.
All right, let her go.
Let her go.
Want me to call
you a cab?
No, I'll walk him home.
It's all right.
Oh, man!
Parker?
I thought
you left for work.
I did.
You're gardening now?
He got out.
I missed the train.
Oh!
Don't say it. No.
Here.
I know what
you're gonna say.
Now here,
let me do this.
You're gonna get filthy.
I'll fill it in. Get the next train.
Okay. Thanks.
And you, you stay.
CATE: He will.
See you tonight. Bye.
Here's a treat.
All right, okay. Okay, just one more.
Just one more. That's it.
Hold on, hold on.
Okay?
Is that good?
Okay.
All right, all right.
This is the last one.
There you go.
Good boy, Hachi.
All right.
Okay. One last one.
There you go.
That's great. That is really great, everybody.
I'm proud of you.
Sorry I was late again.
All right?
I'm off the hook?
WOMAN: Yeah.
Good. Thank you.
(TRAIN HORN WHISTLING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Hey, Hachi.
What are you doing here?
(TRAIN HORN WHISTLING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Hi. Hey, Hachi!
Hey! How you doing?
What are you doing here?
Bedridge Station.
Look at you!
CARL: Yes. Yes, ma'am,
we got one at 7: 30.
You okay?
He been here all day?
No, no, no.
He just showed up
two minutes ago.
He went right there.
You're kidding.
Have you seen Cate?
I haven't seen her.
All right. Okay.
I don't know,
I guess we'll go home.
All right. Okay.
You son of a gun.
Come on.
Come on, boy.
Come on. Come on.
(WATER RUNNING)
ANDY: Mom?
Yeah, sweetie,
I'm in here.
Hey, hi.
Hi.
I got the chips.
Hi, honey. Oh, thanks.
Hey, Mrs. Wilson,
good to see you.
Hi. Oh, Michael,
nice to see you.
Call me Cate.
Okay.
Thank you.
Everything looks
delicious.
Oh, good.
Yeah, that's a great spread.
Why don't you take this to Dad?
Sure.
He's out back.
Let's get this started.
The grill's ready?
It's getting there, yeah.
Nice to see you.
Should I chop these?
You, too.
Yeah, that'd be great, hon.
Let's see...
You know, I actually took guitar lessons
for a little bit, when I was a kid.
Did you?
Yeah, like when I was
nine or 10 years old.
I had to stop because my brother slammed
my fingers in the car door.
I mean, he always said
it was an accident, but after that I just...
I don't know, I stopped practicing.
I wish I didn't, though,
because I really...
It's just, I love music, you know, and I have so
much respect for musicians
and people who
play instruments...
Michael, do you
love my daughter?
Yes, sir. Yes, I do.
Well, that's good because that's what
you want to remember on the bad days.
Right.
Hachi, this is Michael.
Michael, Hachi.
Pleased to meet you.
(SIZZLING)
Hachi. Hey, you wanna play
a little catch?
Yeah? Ready?
Okay, go get the ball. Go get it!
There it is! Get the ball.
It's right there. Go!
Hachi, go get it.
Go! Go get the ball.
Go get it.
Michael, you want
to get that ball back,
you're gonna have to get it yourself.
Hachi doesn't fetch.
He doesn't do it.
Okay.
(ALL GASPING)
Are you all right? Are you okay?
Totally good.
Keep playing. Honey, are you okay?
Are you okay?
Totally.
Are you sure?
I'm gonna get the ball.
Okay.
I'm good.
Look at that.
PARKER:
Are you really okay?
Don't let me
disrupt the game.
Okay. Okay.
Are you all right?
Are you okay?
He was just distracting you there.
Okay.
If I throw the ball just one foot,
you go get it, okay?
Really? Even if I just
toss it right here,
he's not gonna
get it? You're not?
(EXCLAIMING)
KEN: Fetch?
PARKER: Fetch, right.
I throw, he brings back.
He won't do it.
Not Akitas, Parker.
What, they have something
against fetching?
No. You want a dog that fetches,
you get a collie, you get a springer spaniel.
No, Hachi's fine
with me. I'm okay.
Well, good, because Akitas are not
into people-pleasing.
PARKER:
What are they into?
KEN: He comes to the train
because he has a special
connection with you.
"Here, buddy. Go get that ball. "
Why would he do that?
For fun?
For a cookie?
Because it'd make
me happy, basically.
They can't be bought.
They're Japanese,
not American.
Give me a break, man.
Well, if he's gonna fetch,
it'll be for a very special reason.
I'll find a reason.
No, no, no. No, Hach, come on.
You can't go.
I'm sorry, but you can't go.
Come on.
No, stay.
(PARKER SIGHING)
Okay, come on. Come on.
It's all right, come on.
Come on, come on.
Hey, Hach! Hach!
Hach! Hach!
Come on, come on.
(EXCLAIMING PLAYFULLY)
Hey, Hach. Hach!
Let's go. Come on.
Come on! Come on!
Good morning, Milton.
Morning. How are you?
How you doing today?
Myra.
Morning, Parker.
Stay out of the sun.
Good morning,
Mr. Professor.
Hey, good morning.
Good morning, Parker.
He won't bite, huh?
Thank you.
No, no,
he's doing really good.
Come on, boy.
All right, I want you
to go straight home now.
Go straight home.
You'll do that for me?
I'll see you here tonight.
Go ahead. Go on home.
Good boy. Good boy!
Great day,
Carl, isn't it?
Have a good one,
Professor.
Hachi.
There, yes.
Don't tell Milton.
Yeah.
(TRAIN HORN WHISTLING)
Hey, Hachi. Good dog!
What a good boy.
Okay, come on. Let's go home.
Come on.
(CHATTERING)
That's good.
Hey, Hach.
(BARKING)
(WHOOPING)
Come on, come on.
Let's go. Let's go!
Some more champagne?
Is there anymore champagne?
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
PHOTOGRAPHER:
On three. One, two, three.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Hachi!
That's great, Jake.
JAKE: Thanks.
PARKER: Cate.
You seen Hachi?
He wasn't at the station.
No, I haven't seen him
since this morning. Come here.
Look at her.
Can you believe they had her covered
for 30 years?
Isn't she beautiful?
Yeah, she is.
I'm falling
behind schedule.
Oh, you'll catch up.
Just think about opening night.
That'll freak you out.
(LAUGHING)
The young soloist steps downstage,
sings from La Boheme
and then dance, of course.
Following that, rock, rap, hip-hop,
jazz and Hamlet.
And then, of course,
the entire town is going to rise up,
standing ovation.
The place is going crazy.
Mayor sees you down there,
he pulls you up onstage,
puts you center stage and thanks you for
making it all possible.
Yeah?
Yeah.
I like it.
PARKER: Hachi!
Come on, boy.
(HACHI BARKS)
Hachi!
Hachi.
What are you doing here?
It's all right.
Stay, stay.
Hachi, stay.
Okay, go, go away.
Go on, get out.
Get! Get!
Get out of here.
Get out! Get out!
Hachi.
(HACHI BARKING)
(SKUNK CHATTERING)
Come on, come on, come on!
Whoa!
(GROANING)
(SNIFFS)
Parker?
(GASPING)
(EXCLAIMING)
We got skunked.
You want to come
in with us?
No, I'm gonna pass.
Okay.
CATE: You better open a window
before you go to sleep.
You really think
we smell that bad?
(SNEEZING)
You're probably right.
Mom!
Hi, honey. What's up?
I have to tell you something.
Guess what?
What?
Okay, wait.
Just wait. Wait.
What?
See anything different?
No.
Yes!
(EXCLAIMING)
Oh, sweetheart!
That's so wonderful!
Oh, I have to call
Grandma right away.
Okay.
Where's Dad?
Out there, as usual.
Daddy.
Dad.
Dad, what are you doing?
It's a full-body massage.
I'm following the book.
See...
You're gonna be a grandpa.
You gotta get really deep down in
there, in the muscle.
Dad. Dad.
Michael and I are having a baby.
I'm pregnant.
You...
(EXCLAIMING)
Jeez! You're...
Really?
Yes.
You're having a baby?
(LAUGHING)
I'm gonna be a grandpa.
Yes.
Catie!
I can't believe this!
This is terrific, honey.
I'm so happy for you.
Hi, sweetie.
Hey, Mom.
I'm sorry I'm late.
What you got?
I've got all kinds of
healthy things for you.
Fresh-cut vegetables, raspberries,
pita with hummus and sprouts.
CATE: You know, when
I was carrying you,
I was sending out your father for pizza
with red peppers and double anchovies
for weeks straight.
He couldn't even watch me eat it.
(LAUGHING)
Can you believe you and Dad have been
together for 25 years?
We've been together longer
than we've been apart.
Wow.
Dad said after your first date, by the time
he got back to the car,
he missed you so much
he went back for you.
I know. I was watching
from the window.
When I saw him
come up the walk again,
I almost ran out the door
and jumped into his arms.
You should have.
I know.
But I always stop
and think too much.
That's true. You do.
Don't do that.
Okay.
Hey, Hach. Come on, Hachi, come on.
Come on, come on.
(EXCLAIMING)
Yeah! Come on,
let's go home. Let's go home.
Hey, Mr. Professor.
Good night, Parker.
PARKER:
Good night, Mary Anne.
How'd you train
that dog to do that?
MARY ANNE:
That's amazing. Every day.
Let's go.
Parker?
You're overdressed.
(SIGHS)
Well, there's something I might be
able to do about that.
Thank you.
Anything else
you require, madam?
That depends on
what you've got.
Everything.
Everything?
(RUBBER DUCK SQUEAKING)
(LAUGHING)
Yeah, everything.
Okay.
You've had to put up
with a lot. I know that.
I don't know if
I've ever thanked you.
You know how
much I love you?
And I love you.
Good.
Yeah.
Especially when
you don't smell
like a dog or a skunk.
(LAUGHING)
Which isn't very often,
actually, so I should worry about...
Well, it happens
more often...
(PARKER BARKING)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(CATE LAUGHING)
I love you.
Love you, too.
I'll call you later.
Bye-bye.
Okay, Hachi, come on.
Hachi, come on.
(BARKING)
Come on now. What's wrong with you?
Come on.
What is it?
(HACHI BARKS)
Come here,
come here. Come on.
Come here.
What is with you?
Come here now.
You got a problem?
Come here.
You're all right.
What's going on, huh?
You're all right. Okay.
You all right, now?
Okay, come on. Come on.
What's wrong with him?
I don't know.
Hachi, you want to come?
Because I gotta go.
It's a work day. Come on, buddy.
Come on.
I gotta go.
Love you, honey.
Love you, too.
See you tonight.
Last chance.
Bye.
Hey, Mary Anne.
Hey, Jas, how are you?
I'm good.
Here's your coffee and donut.
Oh, thank you, Jasjeet.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Where's Hachi?
(BALL SQUEAKING)
Hey, Hachi!
JASJEET:
There he comes.
(MARY ANNE AND JASJEET
LAUGHING)
Am I happy to see you. What? Did you
bring me your ball?
What is he doing
with a ball?
You want to play catch?
Here. Here. Come here, come here. Here you go.
Go get it.
Okay, go get it.
All right, good.
Now bring it back.
Oh, that's it.
That's what I wanted.
Let's try another one.
Big one. Big long one.
Okay, go get it. Go on.
Good boy!
Yeah! Now bring it back.
Okay, come on.
Come on, boy,
come on, come on!
What a good boy!
Aren't you the good boy!
Did you see that?
I threw the ball,
he brought it back.
First time, a fetch.
A real fetch. Yeah.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
You are a good boy!
Okay, gotta go to work.
Come on, take your ball.
There you go. First time.
First time!
JASJEET: No, no. Wait, wait, wait,
Mr. Professor! Wait, wait.
I'll bring you your coffee right now.
PARKER: All right.
I'm sorry
I'm late today.
Did you see what he did?
I threw the ball, he brought it back.
It was a fetch.
No, no, you keep the ball.
You want me to have that?
I can't play now,
I gotta go to work.
I'll keep the ball,
all right?
Okay.
Here you go.
Okay, thank you.
You're welcome.
And I'll see you at 5: 00.
JASJEET: I'll be here.
Okay. Go home,
Hachi. Go home.
(BARKING)
All right, come here. Come here, come here.
Come here. Come on. Okay.
It's all right.
I'll see you at 5: 00, all right?
Good boy.
Stay, go home. Go on.
Go on.
(PLAYING PIANO)
Was it any better
that time?
(STUDENTS LAUGHING)
All right.
You remember we were talking about
John Philip Sousa,
great march composer
around the turn of the century?
He was a very famous man,
but he had a huge thing
about recorded music.
He would never allow his music
to be recorded.
Even when Thomas Edison
came to him
with his brand-new
invention, the phonograph.
But Edison didn't care.
He went ahead and did it anyhow.
Secretly he recorded
his marching band in a parade.
Which I guess makes it
the very first bootleg.
(STUDENTS CHUCKLE)
So what do you
think about that?
Do you think
Sousa was right?
Do you think it's okay now?
What about today's performers?
Should you be able
to just walk up in the middle of a stage,
plug in your CD player
to a Marshall stack
and that's it?
It's good enough?
I don't know.
I'm a lot older than you,
but I tend to think that
there's an element of music
that cannot be captured.
Life cannot be captured.
The human heart cannot be captured.
The moment of creation
itself is fleeting.
(EXHALING)
(PANTING)
(ALL GASPING)
(STUDENTS MUTTERING)
Hey, Hachi,
how you doing?
Hey, Hachi.
Good night, Hachi.
Hey, buddy.
You ready to go home?
Yeah?
(SIGHING)
(WHIMPERING)
(ANDY SOBBING)
CATE: It's all right.
It's all right.
Hey, Hachi.
Hey, boy.
Is this how he did it?
I'm sorry. I'll learn.
Andy?
It's time to go,
sweetheart.
You're a good boy. You stay here, okay?
I'll be back.
(SNIFFLING)
"I hear and behold
God in every object
"Yet understand
God not in the least
"Nor do I understand
who there can be more wonderful than myself
"In the faces of men
and women I see God
"And in my own face
in the glass
"I find letters from God
dropt in the street
"And every one
is sign'd by God's name
"And I leave them
where they are
"For I know that
wherever I go
"Others will punctually
come forever and ever"
(SIGHING)
Look, you don't have
to wait anymore.
He's not coming back.
All right, Hachi.
You do what you have to do.
(KIDS CHATTERING)
MICHAEL:
Come on, buddy,
come on. Let's go.
Come on, boy. Come on.
ANDY: Come on, Hachi.
Come on, Hachi.
You're gonna be with us now.
Let's go. Come on.
All right, we gotta go.
Ronnie's waiting.
MICHAEL: Come on.
MICHAEL: Let me get that
for you, sweetie.
Come on, Hach.
Up, up, up.
There we go.
That's a good boy. Good.
ANDY: Good boy, Hachi.
MICHAEL:
Watch your head,
watch your head.
Good boy.
(CAR ENGINE STARTING)
(RONNIE COOING)
Hey, there's
my guy. Andy?
ANDY: Yeah?
Hachi! Hachi! Andy!
Hachi!
Hachi, get
back here! Hachi!
Hachi, come on!
Hachi!
(TRAIN RATTLING)
(MEN CHATTERING)
Hey, looks like you
got your first visitor.
Hey there, buddy.
Come to welcome us
to our new home?
Hey, Hach.
JASJEET: Hey, Hachi!
What are you doing here?
Lookie, lookie.
JASJEET: He's going
right to his spot.
MARY ANNE:
I thought he moved away.
He did.
He looks hungry, yeah?
MARY ANNE:
You are a softie, Jas.
JASJEET: Hey, Hachi.
Want a hot dog, boy?
Go on, boy, have a hot dog.
Hey, Hachi.
MARY ANNE: Maybe
it's your cooking, Jas.
The Jasjeet special.
Come on, you'll like it.
Eat it. Eat it. It's good for you.
Come on.
It's good.
Where did he come from?
JASJEET:
Just showed up.
Come on, boy.
Take it.
You better be careful, Hachi.
He's got hot dogs in there older than you.
Don't listen to them, huh?
ANDY: Hachi!
MICHAEL: Oh, God.
Hi! Oh, God,
I was so worried about you.
Why is she just
hanging around him?
It's the professor's daughter.
Really?
CARL: That's where
he's been living.
Will you come home
with me?
Hey, hey, hey...
It's all right.
It's okay.
ANDY: Come on.
Come on.
MICHAEL: Let's go, buddy.
Thank you very much.
Okay.
Thank you!
That's the best thing.
Come on,
give me a coffee.
Jasjeet, come on.
Give me a coffee.
I think of him,
too. Every day.
(TRAIN HORN WHISTLING FAINTLY)
Hey.
You know
we love you, Hachi.
We want you
to stay here with us.
But if you have to go,
that's okay, too.
Okay.
(ANDY LAUGHING)
Goodbye, Hachi.
Good afternoon, Hachi.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Hey, Hachi.
Here you go.
Don't tell Myra,
all right?
Good night, Hachi.
(COLLAR TINKLING)
JASJEET: Hello,
how are you?
WOMAN: I think...
WOMAN: Lucky! Let's go.
Come on, sweetie.
Hey, Lucky.
Hey, girl. Come on,
Lucky, let's go.
Hey, excuse me, sir.
Mmm-hmm.
The dog out there.
Yeah?
Is that the dog
that I've been hearing
so much about?
Mmm-hmm.
What's it to you?
I'm sorry. I'm Teddy Barnes.
I'm with the Woonsocket Call.
Yeah, I've been
hearing a lot of talk
about him on the trains.
I don't know,
sounds like it could
make a good story.
It's Boilins,
Carl Boilins.
B-O-l-L-l-N-S. Yes.
There's no "Y" in there.
I'm the one
that found him,
handed him over.
Oh, yeah?
So, Carl, where's he live?
Well, we're not really sure.
He comes and goes.
Nobody bothers him?
No, we put up with him.
He just does
what he's doing.
Hey, you mind
if I take a picture?
For the newspaper.
I don't mind
if Hachi don't mind.
Thank you very much.
Very nice, very nice.
One without first, please.
Without the dog?
All right. Stay there.
Well, I...
Oh, yeah. All right.
TEDDY: I appreciate it.
That's very kind of you.
(CAMERA CLICKING)
Okay, nice and tight.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Look at that there.
Big smile.
That's... That's beautiful.
Thank you.
Hey, Hachi.
This kid in Derry
sent you his lunch money.
He wants me to buy
you treats with it.
It's like the
third one this week.
If this keeps up,
I'll have to open a bank account for you.
Don't say I never
gave you nothing.
The clog's making out
like a bandit here.
Look at this,
isn't that cute?
Hey, Hach.
JASJEET:
What are you doing
with the money?
I'm his executor.
Be right with you, sir.
CARL ON PA: River Junction
local is now boarding on track
two, it's making all stops.
Hachi.
Here you go, Hachi.
There you are.
Hungry, huh?
Yes, he's very cold.
He must eat.
I'm Jasjeet.
I run the hot dog stand.
I'm Ken Fujiyoshi,
Professor Wilson's friend.
Mr. Professor?
One sugar, two cream.
So then you must have read
the article, then?
I did.
You saw my name
in the article?
(LAUGHING)
Yes, I did.
Twice.
Please, let me help
with the expense.
JASJEET: No, no, no,
please. No money.
KEN: What if he gets sick?
Medical expenses?
We'll take a collection.
From the travelers,
the vendors, and we will
take care of it for him.
JASJEET: The station square
is Hachi's home now.
Every day he comes,
same time, same place,
here only.
You'll do that for him?
Take care of him?
Of course.
JASJEET: All right,
then I...
I've got to sell
some hot dogs.
Good to meet you.
You, too.
Thank you very much.
(IN JAPANESE)
It's been a year, hasn't it?
I wake up sometimes
in the middle of the night
and think about Parker.
He was a good friend.
I understand how you feel.
Hachi, my friend,
Parker is never coming home.
But if Hachiko wants to wait,
then Hachiko should wait.
You want to wait for him,
don't you?
Have a long life Hachi.
(TRAIN HORN WHISTLING)
Come on, mister.
There we are.
That's a good boy.
Want some more?
Okay, come on.
Okay, come on, boy.
Last piece. It's good, huh?
WOMAN: See you
tomorrow, Hachi.
MAN: Ciao, Hachi.
MAN ON PA:
Final call for Oakland,
Wood River Junction
and Four Corners
leaving from track two.
Ms. Wilson?
Nice to see you again.
Good afternoon.
Thank you.
JASJEET: That's the
professor's wife, huh?
(CHATTERING)
KEN: Cate.
Ken.
CATE: It's been a while.
KEN: It certainly has.
It's 10 years.
Can you believe it?
Hi, Hachi.
JASJEET: All right,
have a good one.
MAN 1: Thank you, Jas.
MAN 2: Who would've thought?
WOMAN: I know.
MAN 2: I mean, when we first
went in there, I was like...
Hachi?
You old thing,
you're still waiting.
That's right.
(SNIFFLING)
If it's all right,
could I wait with you
for the next train?
Yeah?
Thanks.
(SNIFFLING)
Oh, Hachi.
RONNIE: That's so cute.
CATE: You like that one?
Yeah.
That's good, isn't it?
That's me.
I know, I remember.
I remember. I was there that day.
I took that picture.
He still looks so cute.
He went to the wedding.
Yeah. He's right there.
Right there.
RONNIE: Where did
Grandpa find Hachi?
CATE: Ronnie, actually,
Hachi found your grandfather.
How?
One night your grandfather was
coming back from a trip.
He got off
at the train station,
he went inside
of the train station...
(TRAIN HORN WHISTLING)
(TRAIN RATTLING)
Hey, boy.
Hey! Come on,
let's go. Come on!
(LAUGHING) Hachi!
Hey, boy.
RONNIE: I never
met my grandfather.
He died when
I was just a baby.
But when I hear about him and Hachi,
I feel like I know him.
They taught me
the meaning of loyalty,
that you should never forget anyone
that you've loved.
And that's why
Hachi will forever
be my hero.
Oh, my God, look how cute he is!
Hi, boy.
He drives me crazy.
Oh, he's happy
to see somebody.
I know.
Can you walk?
Come on, Hachi.
Let's go.
Come on.
Hey, here boy.